A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, American Literary Manuscripts (ALM) collection FA718
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, American Literary Manuscripts (ALM) collection
1958-1989
bulk
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA718
10.12 Cubic Feet
9 document boxes.
Biographical / Historical
The Ford Foundation Archives participated in a survey begun in 1969, conducted by the Committee on Materials of American Literary History of the Modern Language Association (MLA). The result of this survey was the publication in 1977 of American Literary Manuscripts: A Checklist of Holdings in Academic Historical, and Public Libraries, Museums and Author’s Homes in the United States (2nd edition, University of Georgia Press, 1977), edited by J. Albert Robbins. The first edition of American Literary Manuscripts was published by University of Texas Press in 1960. The Ford Foundation participated in the ALM checklist as a manuscript-holding member, but was not a grantor of the ALM project.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access note
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research. All records in this collection are more than 10 years old.
Select records are restricted, as noted.
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Related Archival Materials note
Some folders contain cross-references referring to the file of another individual in the collection.
Scope and Contents note
The American Literary Manuscripts collection is an artificial collection assembled by the Ford Foundation Archive’s staff in the mid 1970s, in response to efforts to compile the second edition of the ALM checklist. The ALM collection includes correspondence; biographical, autobiographical, and financial information; speeches; research reports and other manuscript and typescript items. Documents in the ALM collection were culled from the Ford Foundation’s (1) Grant files, (2) Project files, (3) Log files, and (4) General Correspondence files. The remaining grant, project, log, and general correspondence file material, from which the ALM manuscripts were removed, is stored on microfilm in the Ford Foundation Archive.
The bulk of the Ford Foundation Archives’ holdings cited in the ALM checklist (2nd edition, 1977) was extracted from grant and project files documenting the Humanities and Arts Division’s fellowship programs for creative writers. These programs included:
Grant file 05900121 (PA59-121), PROGRAM FOR CREATIVE WRITERS
Grant file 06000132 (PA60-132), PROGRAM FOR POETS AND FICTION WRITERS
Grant file 06300513 (PA63-513), PROGRAM FOR POETS AND FICTION WRITERS
Project File C-638: Program for the creative writer
Project File C-918: Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets
The following authors appear in the published ALM checklist (2nd edition, 1977) as holdings in the Ford Foundation archive. However, the holdings have either been lost, or loaned out and not returned: Leonie Adams, Conrad Aiken, Robert Anderson, Louis Anchincloss, Marcus Bach, Joseph Freeman, Robert Frost, Caroline Gordon, and Allen Tate.
The following authors appear in the published ALM checklist (2nd edition, 1977) with no holdings accounted for in the Ford Foundation archive. However, the Ford Foundation archive does contain holdings for: Stephen Crane, William Falkner, Donald Finkel, Walter Lippman, Winthrop Sargent, and Thomas Wolfe.
The following authors are represented in the Ford Foundation archive, but do not appear in the published ALM checklist (2nd edition, 1977): Crane Brinton, Henry Commager, Irving Feldman, George Garrett, Rosamond Gilder, Brendan Gill, Wiliam Goyen, john H. Griffin, Oscar Lweis, Russell Lynes, Dwight MacDonald, Paula Marshall, James Boyer Mays, Jean Piaget, Ishmael Reed, James Schevill, Jarvis Thurston, Nicolo Tucci, and Victor Ullman.
Arrangement note
Alphabetical by last name of individual.
Material is arranged as received from the Ford Foundation.
Ford Foundation
- BALDWIN, James, 1958-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-638, Program for the creative writer; and Grant file 05900121 (59-121), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR CREATIVE WRITERS.
- BARAKA, Imamu Amiri (LeRoi Jones), 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- BARTON, Bruce, 1951-1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- BARZUN, Jacques, 1955-1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records,
  Project file B-678, Grants-In-Aid Program in the Behavioral Sciences
  Project file C-629, Master fellowships for graduate school
  Project file C-735, Columbia University - Preservation of the John Jay papers
  Grant file 05600055 (56-55), The Trustees of Columbia University in the City of New York, GRANTS-IN-AID TO FACILITATE RESEARCH IN THE BEHAVIORAL SCIENCES
  Grant file 05900078 (59-78), The Trustees of Columbia University in the City of New York, RESEARCH IN SOCIAL SCIENCES ON BUSINESS PROBLEMS
  Grant file 05900205 (59-205), The Trustees of Columbia University in the City of New York, ASSEMBLY AND ANALYSIS OF DATA ON ECONOMIC EXPECTATIONS AND SPENDING DECISIONS.
  Grant file 05600161 (56-161), The Trustees of Columbia University in the City of New York, ROTATING RESEARCH PROFESSORSHIP IN ECONOMICS
  Grant file 05700371 (57-371), The Trustees of Columbia University in the City of New York, RESEARCH IN THE BEHAVIORAL SCIENCES.
- BELITT, Ben, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- BELLOW, Saul, 1958-1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-638, Program for the creative writer; Grant file 05900121 (59-121), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR CREATIVE WRITERS; Log file #L67-369, “Conference – Situations of the artist, and of institutions in the arts”.
- BENTLEY, Eric, 1958-1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- BLITZSTEIN, Marc, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Includes documents culled from: Grant file 06090118 (60-118), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), COMMISSIONING ASSISTANCE IN CONNECTION WITH AMERICAN OPERATIC REPERTOIRE PROGRAM.
- BLIVEN, Bruce, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- BLY, Robert, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Includes documents culled from Log File #L62-1021, Association of Literary Magazines of America, request for funds.
- BOGAN, Louise, 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Includes documents culled from Project file C-638, Program for the creative writer; Project file C-918, Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets.
- BOLES, Robert (Box 1, Folder 12)
- BONTEMPS, Arna, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 05800368 (58-368), Makerere University, HOUSING FOR VISITING RESEARCH WORKERS AND SCHOLARS.
- BOWEN, Robert O., 1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- BOYLE, Kay, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-918, Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets.
- BRINNIN, John Malcolm, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-638, Program for the creative writer.
- BRINTON, Crane, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- BROOKS, Cleanth, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- BROOKS, Van Wyck, 1955-1959 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- BURKE, Kenneth, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- CALISHER, Hortense (Box 1, Folder 21)
- CARHART, Arthur H., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Log Files #L61-1472, Center for the Accumulation and Preservation of Records, Publications, and other material in the Field of Conservation of Natural Resources in the United States.
- CASSIL, Robert Verlin, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- CHEEVER, John, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Separated Materials
- CHILDRESS, Alice, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- CHILDS, Mark, 1973-1974; 3 folders. (Box 1, Folder 26-28)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 07400330 (74-330), The Washington Journalism Center, Inc., SUPPORT OF A STUDY TO ANALYZE THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN THE MEDIA AND PUBLIC IN THE U. S. BY M. CHILDS AND R. SCAMMON.
- CIARDI, John, 1958-1963 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-638, Program for the creative writer; Project file C-918, Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets.
- CLARK, Walter Van Tilburg, 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- CLEMENS, Walter, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- COMMAGER, Henry, 1955-1962 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grants 05900354 (59-354), Indian School of International Studies, GENERAL PROGRAM; Grants 05500073 (55-73), The Center For Information On America, Incorporated, FOR PUBLICATION AND DISTRIBUTION OF ITS FUTURE VOTERS DISCUSSION GUIDES; Log File #L58-1056, Seminar on American Civilization for Foreign Scholars, Amherst College.
- COUSINS, Norman, 1951-1972; 3 folders. (Box 2, Folder 33-35)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 05390016 (53-16), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), COMMISSION ON TELEVISION; Grant file 06000373 (60-373), Trustees Of Dartmouth College, AMERICAN-SOVIET NON-GOVERNMENTAL SEMINAR ON KEY QUESTIONS RELATING TO PEACE; Grant 06100144 (61-144), Institute Of International Education, Inc., SECOND AMERICAN-SOVIET NONGOVERNMENTAL SEMINAR ON KEY QUESTIONS RELATING TO PEACE; Grant file 07100298 (71-298), Educational Broadcasting Corporation, SUPPORT FOR THE ACTIVITIES OF THE NATIONAL PROGRAMMING COUNCIL FOR PUBLIC TELEVISION.
- COWLEY, Malcolm (Box 2, Folder 36)
- COXE, Louis O., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- CREEKMORE, Hubert (Box 2, Folder 38)
- CUMMINGS, Edward Estlin, 1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 05900121 (59-121), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR CREATIVE WRITERS; Project file C-638, Program for the creative writer.
- DAHLBERG, Edward, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  Edward Dahlberg letter of May 25, 1958 includes references to Ezra Pound. Letter of May 13, 1958 includes references to Robert Creeley.
- DEUTSCH, Babette, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- DICKEY, James (Box 2, Folder 42)
- DODSON, Owen, 1967-1972 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation recoords, Grant file 06890194 (68-194), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), TRAVEL AND STUDY AWARDS.
- DOS PASSOS, John (Box 2, Folder 44)
- EASTLAKE, William, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 06300513 (63-513), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR POETS AND FICTION WRITERS.
- EATON, Evelyn, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- EBERHART, Richard, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- ELLIOTT, George Paul, 1959-1966 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 06300513 (63-513), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR POETS AND FICTION WRITERS; and Project file C-638, Program for the creative writer.
- ELLISON, Ralph, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Log File #L62-1562, Panel on Educational Research, Project on the Difficult 30 percent of the School Population.
- ENGLE, Paul, 1957-1973; 9 folders. (Box 2, Folder 50-54, Box 3, Folder 55-58)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records: Project file C-918, Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets; Log file #L62-40, State University of Iowa, Program in Creative Writing; Grant file 06500332 (65-332), Institute Of International Education, Inc., STRENGTHEN EDUCATIONAL, SCIENTIFIC, AND CULTURAL RELATIONS WITH EAST EUROPEAN COUNTRIES; Grant file 06800890 (68-890), State University Of Iowa Foundation, FELLOWSHIPS FOR LATIN AMERICAN PARTICIPANTS IN THE 1968-1969 INTERNATIONAL WRITING PROGRAM AT THE UNIVERSITY OF IOWA.
- ESHLEMAN, Clayton, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- FARRELL, James T., 1959-1969 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- FAULKNER, William, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 61)
- FELDMAN, Irving, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 62)
- FERLINGHETTI, Lawrence, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 63)
- FIEDLER, Leslie A., 1958-1963 (Box 3, Folder 64)
- FITTS, Dudley, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 65)
- FITZGERALD, Robert, 1958-1967 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 05900121 (59-121), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR CREATIVE WRITERS.
- FLACCUS, Kimball, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 67)
- FOOTE, Shelby, 1963-1967 (Box 3, Folder 68)
- FRANKENBERG, Lloyd, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 69)
- FROST, Robert, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Log File #L59-1460, Trident Films, "Recordings of Great Men of Our Time".
  C.F. Terrell letter of April 26, 1961 contains references to Leonie Adams, Conrad Aiken, and Allen Tate.
- GARDNER, Erle Stanley, 1961-1965 (Box 3, Folder 71)
- GARRETT, George, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 06000132 (60-132), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR POETS AND FICTION WRITERS.
- GARRIGUE, Jean, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 73)
- GELBER, Jack, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 05600014 (56-14), Institute of International Education, Inc., TRAVEL AND STUDY PROGRAM.
- GIBSON, William, 1959-1966 (Box 3, Folder 75)
- GILDER, Rosamond, 1960-1967 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 06600050 (66-50), The American National Theatre And Academy, Inc., SUPPORT FOR THE 1967 CONGRESS OF THE INTERNATIONAL THEATRE INSTITUTE.
- GILL, Brendan, 1958-1963 (Box 3, Folder 77)
- GOLD, Herbert, 1959-1965 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 06000032 (60-132), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), FOREIGN AREA TRAINING FELLOWSHIP PROGRAM, 1960-61.
- GOODMAN, Paul, 1959-1965 (Box 3, Folder 79)
- GORDON, Caroline, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 80)
- GOYEN, William, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 81)
- GREEN, Paul, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Log file #L61-1216, Penn Community Services, Inc., “Production of a Negro Folk Drama”.
- GREGOR, Arthur, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 83)
- GREGORY, Horace, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 84)
- GRIFFIN, John H., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 85)
- HAGEDORN, Hermann, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Log file #L58-84, Theodore Roosevelt Centennial, Support for proposed Fourth Of July observance.
- HALL, Donald, 1958-1963 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-638, Program for the creative writer; and Project file C-918, Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets.
- HALL, Oakley, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 88)
- HARRIS, Mark, 1958-1965 (Box 4, Folder 89)
- HART, Moss, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-622: Grants in Aid program for directors in theater.
- HATCHER, Harlan H., 1953-1970; 4 folders. (Box 4, Folder 91-94)
  Includes documents culled the following Ford Foundation Grant files documenting grants to the University of Michigan:
  Missing Title
  06700060 (PA67-60)
  EXTENSION OF THE DATA ON AMERICAN VOTING COLLECTED BY THE INTER-UNIVERSITY CONSORTIUM FOR POLITICAL RESEARCH
  06600201 (PA66-201)
  NATIONAL FAMILY PLANNING PROGRAM IN MALAYSIA
  06600151 (PA66-151),
  SURVEY OF THE EXTENT TO WHICH LOW-INCOME FAMILIES BENEFIT FROM PRIVATE HOUSING CONSTRUCTION
  06400084 (PA64-84)
  STUDY OF UNION-MANAGEMENT POLICIES INTRODUCTION OF TECHNOLOGICAL CHANGES IN THE TRANSPORTATION INDUSTRIES
  06300318 (PA63-318)
  FELLOWSHIP PROGRAM IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION AND ECONOMICS 1963-1964
  06300039 (PA63-39)
  GRANT-IN-AID TO FACILITATE RESEARCH IN THE BEHAVIORAL SCIENCES
  06100271 (PA61-271)
  FELLOWSHIP PROGRAM IN ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT AND ADMINISTRATION 1961-1962
  06100213 (PA61-213)
  SUMMER PROGRAM ON APPLICATIONS OF MATHEMATICS TO BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION
  06100166 (PA61-166)
  STRENGTHENING OF PREPARATION FOR COLLEGE TEACHING
  06100146 (PA61-146),
  USA - USSR EXCHANGE OF BEHAVIORAL SCIENTISTS
  06000466 (PA60-466
  BASIC RESEARCH IN THE BEHAVIORAL SCIENCES
  06000428 (PA60-428)
  CONFERENCE TO EVALUATE NATIONAL DEFENSE EDUCATION ACT GRADUATE LANGUAGE FELLOWSHIP PROGRAM
  06000263, (PA60-263)
  RESEARCH AWARDS FOR DEVELOPMENT OF NEW CONCEPTS AND PRACTICES OF DELINQUENCY PREVENTION AND CONTROL
  06000140 (PA60-140)
  SUMMER SEMINAR ON PROBLEMS OF STABILITY AND GROWTH IN THE NATIONAL INCOME
  05900501 (PA59-501)
  TRAINING JAPANESE TEACHERS OF ENGLISH
  05900055 (PA59-55)
  ENGLISH LANGUAGE INSTITUTE
  05700055 (PA57-55)
  STIMULATION OF PUBLICATION IN THE HUMANITIES AND SOCIAL SCIENCES BY THE UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN PRESS
  05600184 (PA56-184)
  1957 MIDWEST SEMINAR IN AMERICAN FOREIGN POLICY
  05600166 (PA56-166)
  PROBLEM-ORIENTED RESEARCH IN ECONOMICS AND/OR BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file A-529: University of Michigan, Behavioral Sciences. See also: Ford Foundation, Grants, 05000255 (PA50-255), Regents of the University of Michigan, INDIVIDUAL BEHAVIOR AND HUMAN RELATIONS RESEARCH.
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Log file #L61-1288, “Venezuela-Peru mission”.
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 05700381 (PA57-381), University of Chicago, BASIC RESEARCH IN THE BEHAVIORAL SCIENCES.
- HAWKES, John C. B., Jr., 1963 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 06500013 (65-13), American Arbitration Association, Inc., RESEARCH SEMINARS ON THE NATURE AND IMPLICATIONS OF CONTINUOUS DIALOGUE IN COLLECTIVE BARGAINING.
- HECHT, Anthony, 1959-1965 (Box 4, Folder 96)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-918, Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets; and Grant file 06000132 (60-132), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR POETS AND FICTION WRITERS.
- HELLMAN, Lillian, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 97)
- HICKS, Granville, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 98)
- HOFFMAN, Daniel, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 99)
- HOLLANDER, John, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 100)
- HORGAN, Paul, 1959-1962 (Box 4, Folder 101)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 06200234 (62-234), The Opera Association Of New Mexico, SYMPOSIUM FOR YOUNG COMPOSERS IN CONNECTION WITH A STRAVINSKY FESTIVAL IN SANTA FE.
  J. Crosby letter of February 3, 1962 includes references to W.H. Auden and T.S. Eliot.
- HOWE, Irving, 1963-1973 (Box 4, Folder 102)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 07100072 (71-72), Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY), SUPPORT FOR A CONFERENCE ON THE WORLD OF THE BLUE COLLAR WORKER AND FOR PUBLICATION OF THE CONFERENCE PAPERS.
- HUGHES, Langston, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-638, Program for the creative writer; and Project file C-613: American Council on Germany Inc., "Conference for American and German Foreign Policy Leaders". See also Ford Foundation Grant file 05800305 (58-305).
- HUMPHREY, William, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 104)
- INGE, William, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 105)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Log file #L59-480, Conference – Young Professionals in the Arts.
- JACKSON, Shirley, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 106)
- JEROME, Judson, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 107)
- JONES, Madison, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 108)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Log file #L62-713, New York City Commission on Human Rights.
- JUSTICE, Donald, 1958-1965 (Box 5, Folder 109)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-918, Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets; and Grant file 06300513 (63-513), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR POETS AND FICTION WRITERS.
- KAZIN, Alfred, 1958-1960 (Box 5, Folder 110)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Log file #L57-477, Program for Poland; and Project file C-638, Program for the creative writer.
- KENNEDY, John F., 1956-1963; JFK's signature has been cut out from the June 28, 1956 letter to H. Rowan Gaither. The JFK signature went missing before June 1977, as noted in the "Ford Foundation Letter" (newsletter), issued on June 1, 1977. (Box 5, Folder 111)
  Includes documents culled from Log file #L56-727, “Sponsorship of nation-wide high school essay contest to assist in selecting five outstanding senators”; Log file #L57-141, “Staff Study on the Aging as a Field for Foundation Interest”; Log file #L61-1151, Joint Council on Economic Education, “Develop Integrated Program for Social Studies in Secondary Schools”; and Grant file 06300574 (63-574), United Negro College Fund, Inc., CAPITAL FUND CAMPAIGN.
- KERR, Walter, 1957-1969 (Box 5, Folder 112)
- KING, Martin Luther, Jr., 1966-1971 (Box 12, Folder 113)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 06700580 (67-580), Southern Christian Leadership Foundation, SUPPORT OF A PROGRAM FOR NEGRO CHURCH LEADERSHIP IN FIFTEEN CITIES; Grant file 07000178 (70-178), Southern Christian Leadership Foundation, SUPPORT TO MAKE POSSIBLE PURCHASE OF FILM PRINTS FOR 3/24/70 BENEFIT SHOWING OF KING: A FILMED RECORD MONTGOMERY TO MEMPHIS.
- KINGSLEY, Sidney, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 114)
- KINNELL, Galway, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 115)
- KNOWLES, John, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 116)
- KOCH, Kenneth (Box 5, Folder 117)
- KRONENBERGER, Louis, 1957-1961 (Box 5, Folder 118)
- KUBLY, Herbert, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 119)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-918: Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets; and Project file C-623: Grants in Aid program for the playwright in theater.
- KUNITZ, Stanley, 1958-1961 (Box 5, Folder 120)
- LaFARGE, Oliver, 1958-1963 (Box 5, Folder 121)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-918, Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets; and Log file #L57-1150, Museum of Navajo Ceremonial Art.
- LATTIMORE, Richmond, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 122)
- LAUGHLIN, James, 1953-1963; 8 folders. (Box 5, Folder 123-130)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 05300033 (53-33), Intercultural Publications, Inc., REIMBURSEMENT FOR ADVANCE MADE FROM APPROPRIATION FOR PERSPECTIVES, USA TO FINANCE EXPANDED ACTIVITIES OF THE CORP.; Grant file 05400008 (54-8), Intercultural Publications, Inc., INTERNATIONAL CULTURAL EXCHANGE PROGRAM; Grant file 05400089 (54-89), Intercultural Publications, Inc., PUBLICATION OF .COUNTRY PERSPECTIVES. IN CONJUNCTION WITH THE ATLANTIC MONTHLY; Grant file 05600103 (56-103), Intercultural Publications, Inc., PERSPECTIVE OF GERMANY; Grant file 05700081 (57-81), Intercultural Publications, Inc., PUBLICATION OF .PERSPECTIVE OF BURMA; Project file B-96, All India Fine Arts and Crafts Society, Second International Contemporary Art Exhibition; Project file B-433, Delhi University (see also Grant file 05500164 [55-164]); and Project file C-110, Intercultural Publications, Inc. (see also Grant 05700081 [57-81]).
- LAVERY, Emmett, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 131)
- LEACH, Henry G., 1953-1959 (Box 6, Folder 132)
- LEWIS, Janet, 1959-1963 (Box 6, Folder 133)
- LEWIS, Oscar, 1953-1967 (Box 6, Folder 134)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Log file #L61-1106, Study of Culture Change in Cuba.
- LIEBERMAN, Elias, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 135)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Log file #L60-893, Newspaper Coverage of Economics and Business.